so thank you so much for joining with us
um and congratulations uh the first set
of bids have been received in terms of
the primary interest in idbi Banks take
sale so give us a sense of what has been
the response uh you know we know at
times it's difficult for the government
to actually develop details but uh you
know give us a sense like when you say
multiple what does that really mean
well I think the transaction advisor uh
he has advised that there's been good
response
so we don't as per our process they
don't reveal the names and the number
for maintaining Integrity of our bidding
process so I would not be in a position
to tell you the number on the names but
suffices to say there's a good response
good response multiple bids so uh you
know at least at our end we can safely
assume that at least three and more bids
have come in and again in terms of the
potential sectors which are represented
mainly Banks non-banks or is it a
healthy mix
well it's a healthy mix both domestic
and fun
excellent excellent so what is the next
uh in terms of the process now going
forward uh would you be inviting the
financial bids uh pretty soon or it will
have its own timeline
now after uh after the initial bids come
in there is a question of you know
checking the beds and the prepares which
the transaction advisor does
also there is a fit and proper in this
case involved right in the beginning
with the RBI you've done that at the U.S
state as well yeah this is a stage at
which it will be done by the RBI now
that the bills have come in once the
bids are coming in and accordingly I
think there will be submitting papers to
the qualified ones will be submitting
papers to the RBI we have a virtual data
room then it will be opened under the
non-disclosure undertaking where there
will be sufficient non material which is
not in public domain uh in respect of
that there will be greater amounts of
information that will be made available
to the bidders and also subsequently the
draft share purchase agreement and other
definitive documents the drafts of that
will be shared for their response so
this is what is called a due diligence
process
once that's completed then the RFP is
issued for the invite of the financial
correct so how
expect this
when do you actually plan to call the
financial bids will it be after the due
diligence process or maybe by March well
the timing actually does depend on
transaction to transaction it depends
upon the complexity of the transaction
the nature of this whether the site
visits are to be planned whether uh you
know what kind of assets uh transaction
in that particular company has so it
depends this is a bank I think it's more
like in the nature of financial
information and accounting information
not in terms of as much on the physical
aspects but nevertheless I think uh
three to four months is a minimum time
which is required for due to diligence
process okay so you will be inviting the
financial bids only post that that's
right okay and you will be well into the
new Financial year uh by then so a
tentative timeline uh would be some time
closing the transaction Maybe by Next
Gen so
or even before that I think that will be
much earlier than that but it will be in
fi 24 but it will be I think much
earlier than that okay so maybe before
the current calendar year let us know
let us hope and we'll we'll keep you
informed how it goes right right so you
mentioned foreign domestic boats so uh
do you think in hindsight the fact that
you know you uh you know gave three very
clear categories Banks nbfcs P firms uh
you know all of them can come in and a
lot of work was done between you and RBI
and the other Regulators so you think
that is now kind of paying dividends and
will pay dividends in the months to come
now I think the right from beginning our
effort has been since this is the first
uh you know transaction of its kind to
give sufficient Clarity and also make it
as larger as open a process to have a
competitive bidding see key to our
process have been always stressing is
the uh you know availability of
competitive bids the size of the
transaction where most people will be
find comfortable so we don't design our
process for uh you know one or two
players but for a larger number of
players so there's a greater amount of
bidding and then there is obviously we
would like the maximum amount of you
know max value maximization of a value
of shares this is uh these shares in the
government for example belong to the
government of India and of course LIC
shares or LIC has its own shareholders
and policyholders and so on so it's very
important for us that we do the process
in a competitive Manner and we discover
the best value so that's what is now
going to unfold I mean the process is
going to be the bidding is going to be
competitive we can expect that yes
please okay so in the past sometimes uh
you know and check me if I'm wrong uh
you know there were certain discussions
way back you know five six years back
and there was some indication that maybe
around you know 80 to 85 would have been
a good bid
and we really don't know what happened
post that so what what I'm just trying
to ask probably is that whatever was
there in the past will that also be a
factor for the government to decide you
know the pricing of the bids as and how
the process unfolds or you think that
this is a fresh clean slate and you know
whatever you know whatever comes forward
and whatever the reserve price they come
in decides at a later point in time that
is how it's going to be the past is not
going to cast a shadow
so this is a price Discovery process so
we are out in the market to discover the
price rather than the other way around
we don't determine the price and do it
the benchmarking price or the reserve
price is only an internal process for us
to satisfy ourselves that you know
we are not really you know
uh in in a way
selling it you know very below part but
what exactly is the price is for the
market to discover and a competitive Pro
bidding process ensures that besides uh
any company you know what it is what is
its value keeps on changing as you know
in a dynamic economy very fast it
depends upon you know it's not
necessarily only depends upon the past
but it is a lot to do with future it's
present context and its future setting
so it's a very complex process as you
know and that's the reason why people
you know different bidders would value
it differently even though you know
technically speaking we have the same
quantitative processes in Investment
Banking but the fact that you know the
people attach different value to
different price because essentially the
valuation or discover price at the end
of the day is also a subjective thing
based on assumptions about the future
okay so one or two uh concerns over here
you know uh you know some uh some
experts or other in some quarters there
is this impression that uh
you know the Legacy and peers of idbi
Bank could still be a concern uh you
know you know aging or npas of course
the provisioning Norms come down but
that could still be an overhang uh what
does the government's take on this could
this be a stumbling block and the times
to come maybe not looking at the way the
you've got a good response quote unquote
on the primary bid so far I don't think
so
because I think a lot of work has
already been done on the health of the
idbi bank over a period of time not only
in terms of capitalization which was
done but also the you know the net NPA
is what counts and that has been very
very uh so you don't think that overhang
is going to be there okay uh so also uh
you know you have been now post
divestment your share in idbi will be
come to this public share holiday sebi
has given Clarity on that front uh there
are certain terms in condition attached
to that so with the GUI be meeting all
of those you will not have a seat on the
board you will not have you know or
voting rights have so have so far been
defined by semi so I'm going to meet all
those three four terms and conditions if
you have read it correctly that was
initially The Proposal
that was basically our proposal because
it is the the government when it's
mindful that if it is uh wanting it to
be you know sort of designated as public
that doesn't mean you know you can't be
promoted in the public at the same time
so it's clearly we are getting off the
promotership and that was our proposal
which the sebi has agreed okay uh so
what about LIC we're going to understand
that LIC probably also has made a pitch
in terms of treating their shareholding
as public we don't really know what has
been the response so far so is it on
board is it not on board has
semi-directed or accepted and either
ways how does that really look
I think that's not really a very
important issue because LIC if maybe LIC
in future would be public when it brings
down the shareholding to a certain level
which maybe wants it to so it's for the
government that we wanted to be very
clear about because uh there I think the
you know whether to be directed whether
to have director or not to have a
director LIC is is at the end of the day
is there in different companies of
course when it is there in different
companies as an investor it has to bring
it down to a certain level and if it is
exceeding a level maybe at that level it
might not be granted a public status but
in future yes when they when they bring
the
because both LIC and government do not
intend to stay on there it's only an
interim Arrangements that we are there
as a financial investor uh both in terms
of the size of the transaction that it
would mean also because of the upside
that we might like to take it in post
this investment okay so in both cases I
think both LIC and government they would
like eventually to exit uh in a in a
time frame which will be defined in
future okay uh but basically as of now
has the regulator given Clarity on lic's
uh pitch so anything you can share with
us
now that's not the concern I think we in
the government was wanting to do it push
its own okay thing and therefore that
proposal has been agreed okay okay so
LIC special probably was not a material
concern what was material was in
government space got that uh also sir uh
you know you have also amended the scra
rules in terms of the minimum public
shareholding Norms uh you know sebi is
not uh semi is not so far says uh
idea Bank Post divestment will have to
meet the MPS Norms within one year but
at the same time government has amended
the rules or on the other hand so how do
you see both of them panning out and
will you be giving a Clarity on you know
extension or exemption from MPS any kind
of kind of a deadline that you are
looking at so far the timeline has not
been expressed and will that overrule uh
what sebby has brought out the one year
timeline to meet MPS for idbi attack
see the scrr rule is a generic thing it
doesn't really you know it's not really
for only for the idbi bank it's in
general for the government uh you know a
certain category where the government
has substantial holding or the public
sector companies have the substantial
Holdings there you know it is basically
sometimes
meetings
yes I mean it sometimes it becomes
difficult for them to achieve MPS in a
time frame in which is required also
because you know uh as a government
undertakings and all that some may not
be doing well and if in order to do that
they may not be takers for example for
some in some cases for example Bank a
reverse thing has happened where
government had to recapitalize so even
something like idbi bank which was an
MPS earlier it had to slip into a
non-mps category so there are different
things which emerge and I think in order
to meet that eventuality and that is not
really a general blanket thing it's only
a power to exam Case by case and also to
for a particular period right so what is
that so only the notification has the
the new rules have made it clear that
number one I mean it's it's clarified
the land language which is already there
since 2021 secondly I think the
explanation has also been added that uh
you know it it will not really disrupt
this strategic disinvestment process in
certain cases for example if you have
given this one fine morning you know if
it gets out and doesn't fit into that
public sector definition
then it can't can't lose the thing and
it has to have a transition period which
was granted which was granted earlier in
the first place so because that is
granted to a to a company
to an entity and it is not to you know
whether the ownership now based on you
know ownership change all of a sudden
overnight if you do that that will be uh
unfair okay and I think that is the
eventuality which has been on boarded
and scrr rules in fact takes away it's a
generic rules and within that a specific
notification that needs to be issued so
what is the kind of deadline that you're
thinking of in terms of extension of the
uh of meeting the MPS norms
no I mean that will be it will be there
as on date in fact idbi Bank enjoys that
uh exemption 24 so I mean it will be
really clarified in due course as to
which is a period in which MPS must be
met
[Music]
idbi Bank along with the subsidiaries
and Associates Associates is being
domestic is that what you have proposed
or it's going to be a separate exercise
no I think at this moment that's the one
okay okay together
along with the main back okay sir uh so
also just wanted to understand on a
philosophical philosophical level uh you
know what would be the government's
preference uh would it be more in terms
of PE investors uh you know who may look
upon the entire deal transaction uh as
more of a financial investment or
financial returns rather than a
strategic player like Banks you know
what would be the preference of the
government a very philosophical level I
want to ask them there is no philosophy
into it and there is no preference into
it once we have defined our rules of the
game once we have given that everyone is
an equal fitting putting and who
whosoever will bid the highest will get
it so there is in any competitive
bidding process is no question of a
choice here then we have said that these
are the equals within the equals
whosoever actually bids the highest gets
it okay uh and so in case it
I'm just asking hypothetically over here
so do they have to couple in the form of
a consortia because you will need
somebody to drive the bank right could
you explain something on that front door
no that has not been our structure okay
even any PE can also come in singly
which was uh okay so the Consortium was
uh you know was not a mandatory
requirement okay
fine but it could come as a Consortium
but not as a mandatory requirement okay
okay and in case it's a bank then of
course uh you know they will have their
own license at the moment uh idbi has a
deemed license so how does that work sir
well the licensing has been made very
clear that you know if it were a bank to
which were to bid then the license there
will be only one license posters
investment so there has to be a merger
okay okay sir right sir right so also in
terms of you know the the way the
markets have been you know one question
that is uh probably asked frequently is
the fact that uh when you know private
promoters have done so well in terms of
diversity their own Stakes you know big
numbers are being given out uh you know
could the government have been more
proactive on his disinvestment agenda so
what could be your assessment and your
response the government has been always
telling that we will go for a calibrated
way of disinvestment keep in in mind the
you know the minority shareholders
interests which are also there so and uh
in case of privatization of course where
the management control is passed
it has to be again uh you know in a
calibrated way when a transaction is
announced and then we try to take it to
a logical you know conclusion to the
bidding process okay calibrated is the
is the is the watchword there also so in
terms of your residual stake in suti
would you be selling out from ITC if yes
you know what is the rough plan on that
front if not so why not
no I think uh suti there is a you know
administrators then there are they they
look into it and from time to time they
take decisions so I am not really
responding that you know when and what
and again as much as we would not really
like to reveal when and what and we will
we will like to come to an ofs or try to
disinvest well I think we have to meet
with the sebi norms and uh and act
accordingly okay so would you be in
principle closed towards selling for the
second ITC or in principle note not
really open-ended but not decided no we
I'm I would not like to comment on these
specific things okay okay so also in
terms of terms of the big strategic
disinvestments now uh how do you see the
coming Financial year uh you know do we
understand that of course idbi would be
the big one you know along with probably
a shipping Corporation Concord uh give
us a give us an idea give us give us an
assessment of how you're looking at the
new Financial year we are all all
looking for the ongoing transactions
which are at different stages they
should be concluded as per the process
and I think that is what we would like
to do okay but any particular ones
particularly that you know you're very
hopeful of no I mean I think I am
hopeful for all of them correct correct
so no order of preference in that no
there is uh there is no question of a
preference it's a cabinet mandate and
certain things are announced and I think
we must carry them forward right and
conclude them right suspect
on Sci and BML could you just share with
us what is the current
currency and uh you know are you still
very hopeful of BML going forward
because again you know some people have
been saying some quotas are saying that
maybe you know not very sure whether the
bidders are still in the race or not
could you give your assessment
now our transaction advisors
informants that we are all you know
moving forward and of course I think the
in BML case the even the demerger
process has also been done and only now
listing Remains the same thing is about
nmdc steel where demeriter has been done
a listing remains and in sci the
demerger order is abated okay so these
are the kind of things which are which
require demerger because of hiving of
non-core assets which was a requirement
and I think it took really time around
it but we will definitely move forward
post that okay so you can expect you can
call you may be calling for the
financial bids by March in some time or
maybe slip into the financial well I
would I would say that it will depend
upon when they're ready and transaction
advisor advises and the listing happens
yes so this also talk about mmtc the
fact that the government is very close
to finalizing the closure of mmtc could
you please give us an idea about where
we stand on that front and there are a
couple of companies the government has
been looking for a period of time in
terms of closure so anything that you
would like to share sir no there is
nothing uh as far as mmtc is concerned
okay okay but there have been reports
saying that uh there could be reports
but reports are there all the time but
okay not to my knowledge okay so also
another uh you know talking point has
been government's plan to sell off stake
in fertilizer companies being the
non-surgic sector so could you share
something with us on that front I mean
there was a lot of Buzz around six odd
months back but then we're not hearing
much on that front now and then the
issue keeps dropping up so anything that
you would like to share so is it still
or not on again I'm not really aware you
know whether any such thing is there
uh I think media keeps speculating you
have right to speculate because once you
have new PSC policy you will keep on
speculating but there is no such thing
yet okay so answer one of the last
questions
um uh you know how do you look at your
pipeline for fi 24 both in terms of ofs
36s are full your bag is going to be
full on that front but how do you see
the coming Financial year going forward
and uh I know uh you know the government
is very clear that uh divestment aim is
one thing but actually doing the work on
the ground is another thing but how do
you look at the whole thing you know
what about your numbers uh is there
pressure to meet them and would you like
the targets to be modest moderate or
realistic anything that you can share
with us I can only say that honorable
Finance Minister will announce the
budget and we will carry forward and we
have been you know whatever ongoing
transactions we move forward on that
okay uh okay fine uh nothing in terms of
uh then you know number should be
realistic or modest or moderate or
nothing of that kind right so thank you
very much for giving time to CNBC TV
waiting we'll keep coming back to you
for more inputs thank you very much
[Music]